<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simulation | ...a sea of data...</title>
    <link>https://d-lorenz.github.io/tag/simulation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://d-lorenz.github.io/tag/simulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Simulation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All rights reserved © Lorenzo D&#39;Andrea 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:26:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://d-lorenz.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Simulation</title>
      <link>https://d-lorenz.github.io/tag/simulation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>smartR</title>
      <link>https://d-lorenz.github.io/project/smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:26:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d-lorenz.github.io/project/smart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SMART (Spatial MAnagement of demersal Resources for Trawl fisheries), a tool for assessing bio-economic feedback in different management scenarios. smartR combines information from different tasks gathered within the European Data Collection Framework on fisheries and is composed of: 1) spatial models of fishing effort, environmental characteristics and distribution of demersal resources; 2) an Artificial Neural Network which captures the relationships among these aspects in a spatially explicit way and uses them to predict resources abundances; 3) a deterministic module which analyzes the size structure of catches and the associated revenues, according to different spatially-based management scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantis</title>
      <link>https://d-lorenz.github.io/project/mantis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:25:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d-lorenz.github.io/project/mantis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marine protected Areas Network Towards Sustainable fisheries in the Central Mediterranean is a three year project funded by the European Commission – DG Maritime Affairs and Fisheries (DG MARE) under the theme“ Marine protected areas: network(s) for enhancement of sustainable fisheries in EU Mediterranean waters Mare/2014/41.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating the effects of alternative management measures of trawl fisheries in the Central Mediterranean Sea: application of a multi-species bio-economic modelling approach</title>
      <link>https://d-lorenz.github.io/publication/russo-2019-simulating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://d-lorenz.github.io/publication/russo-2019-simulating/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
