<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | ...a sea of data...</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All rights reserved © Lorenzo D&#39;Andrea 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:26:21 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>smartR</title>
      <link>/project/smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:26:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/smart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SMART (Spatial MAnagement of demersal Resources for Trawl fisheries), a tool for assessing bio-economic feedback in different management scenarios. smartR combines information from different tasks gathered within the European Data Collection Framework on fisheries and is composed of: 1) spatial models of fishing effort, environmental characteristics and distribution of demersal resources; 2) an Artificial Neural Network which captures the relationships among these aspects in a spatially explicit way and uses them to predict resources abundances; 3) a deterministic module which analyzes the size structure of catches and the associated revenues, according to different spatially-based management scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vmsbase</title>
      <link>/project/vmsbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:26:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/vmsbase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VMSbase is an R package devised to manage, process and visualize information about fishing vessels activity (provided by the vessel monitoring system - VMS) and catches/landings (as reported in the logbooks). VMSbase is primarily conceived to be user-friendly; to this end, a suite of state-of-the-art analyses is accessible via a graphical interface. In addition, the package uses a database platform allowing large datasets to be stored, managed and processed vey efficiently. Methodologies include data cleaning, that is removal of redundant or evidently erroneous records, and data enhancing, that is interpolation and merging with external data sources. In particular, VMSbase is able to estimate sea bottom depth for single VMS pings using an on-line connection to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) database. It also allows VMS pings to be assigned to whatever geographic partitioning has been selected by users. Standard analyses comprise: 1) métier identification (using a modified CLARA clustering approach on Logbook data or Artificial Neural Networks on VMS data); 2) linkage between VMS and Logbook records, with the former organized into fishing trips; 3) discrimination between steaming and fishing points; 4) computation of spatial effort with respect to user-selected grids; 5) calculation of standard fishing effort indicators within Data Collection Framework; 6) a variety of mapping tools, including an interface for Google viewer; 7) estimation of trawled area. Here we report a sample workflow for the accessory sample datasets (available with the package) in order to explore the potentialities of VMSbase. In addition, the results of some performance tests on two large datasets (1×105 and 1×106 VMS signals, respectively) are reported to inform about the time required for the analyses. The results, although merely illustrative, indicate that VMSbase can represent a step forward in extracting and enhancing information from VMS/logbook data for fisheries studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minouw</title>
      <link>/project/minouw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/minouw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project’s overall objective is the gradual elimination of discards in European marine fisheries. We aim to minimise unwanted catches by incentivising the adoption of technologies and practices that reduce bycatch and discards, and avoid damage to sensitive marine species and habitats.
Our goal is to develop and demonstrate technological and socio-economic solutions that enable and incentivise fishermen to 1) avoid unwanted catches, or 2) where this cannot be reasonably or practically achieved, to utilise them productively and sustainably.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantis</title>
      <link>/project/mantis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:25:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/mantis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marine protected Areas Network Towards Sustainable fisheries in the Central Mediterranean is a three year project funded by the European Commission – DG Maritime Affairs and Fisheries (DG MARE) under the theme“ Marine protected areas: network(s) for enhancement of sustainable fisheries in EU Mediterranean waters Mare/2014/41.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
